SANKAR ANAND

(508) 333-7074 • sankar.anand.th@gmail.com • www.linkedin.com/in/sankaranandth

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Seasoned professional with 8 years of technical experience and business acumen mix at high-growth tech and Fortune 500 firms. Drove programs, partnering with supply chain, sales, accounts, product and data science, to scope business requirements, deliver actionable reporting, manage risk mitigation, lead project planning, influence product map and execute strategic initiatives.

Languages/Tools: SQL (Presto, MySQL, PLSQL), Tableau, Python, MS Office (Advanced Excel), G-Suite (Sheets, Slides), Jira Databases: Snowflake, Salesforce, Oracle Supply Chain Planning, Kinaxis Rapidresponse Demand Planning Specialties: Data Analytics, Scrum Fundamentals Certified, BI Reporting, Program Management, Lean Six Sigma Green Belt

WORK EXPERIENCE

Various Firms

Independent Consulting

Mar 2024 – Present

- Analyzed current state of business operations, conducted value stream mapping and recommended process improvements for a transportation client, resulting in truck cost savings of \$500k annually.
- Conducted inventory optimization analysis for a client, to trim slow moving inventory, resulting in savings of \$350k.

Convoy, Inc

Sr Program Manager, Customer Insights & Experience.

Jul 2022 - Oct 2023

- Increased active monthly users of Convoy BI tool, Convoy Web, by 45%. Worked directly with customers and account teams to understand product gaps, provided feature requests to product and supported promotional activities.
- Executed the company's first customer sentiment program to capture voice of customer (VOC) feedback to influence product roadmap, present feedback findings and customer pain points to leadership and create actionable recommendations.
- Performed deep dive analysis on scheduling and operational problems at an enterprise customer warehouse facility and improved carrier ratings from 3.5 to 4.4/5, reduced truck costs by 45% and eliminated excess wait time.
- Developed a churn predictive model with data science for at-risk customers, improving customer retention by 30%.
- Built playbooks and trained 4 new analysts to use current systems and process frameworks and completed ramp up in 4 weeks.

Honeywell Intelligrated Systems

Technical Program Manager, Supply Chain Planning

Dec 2020 – May 2022

- Led significant program leading launch of Kinaxis Rapidresponse within budget and on time, interfacing with senior leaders, building solution design, managing budget/resources, setting up testing phases, mitigating risks and aligning stakeholders
- Orchestrated IT coordination to develop analytical tools and date pipelines for business users from Oracle Supply Chain Planning for inventory forecasts, inventory space projections, capacity plans, burndown plans and weekly clear-to-build projections.
- Led a significant program involving 6 internal teams and 3 senior leaders implementing an independent forecast plan and process for 2000+ raw material SKUs in Oracle ERP.
- Implemented an adhoc ETL process using python and PLSQL to automate mass uploads of PO data to/from Oracle, reducing past due orders by 60% and shortage risks by 47% for procurement teams.
- Analyzed material usage data from Oracle across 10+ product lines, deployed plan for every part (PFEP) process and updated safety stock levels to reduce excess inventory by 45%.

Uber Technologies, Inc

Program Manager, Customer Operations

Jan 2018 – Jun 2020

- Led a crossfunctional project team of 6 people managers to restructure the customer support department, centralize teams, standardize processes, and redesign escalation workflows to improve efficiency and reduced \$4.3M in opex costs.
- Led a project team of three analysts to reduce \$14 million in revenue losses from accessorial fee underpayments from customers through process improvement, additional reporting, creating a dedicated ops team and identifying product solutions.
- Partnered with product teams to improve escalation process efficiency for support teams by 20%. Scoped the business need, identified automation opportunities, created project execution plan and coordinated between crossfunctional teams.
- Drove performance improvement initiatives that reduced overlap in team roles, developed clear KPIs, revamped job ladder and addressed competency gaps in current support and account teams.
- Developed "cost of service" metric to drive account and support team efficiency and workforce planning efforts.

Global Group Africa

Supply Chain Analyst, Supply Chain Planning

Jun 2013 – Sep 2015

- Reduced \$1.2M in excess inventory through optimizing warehousing processes, data modelling and supply chain strategy.
- Collaborated with sales account managers to forecast, track, and report out weekly on key customer and inventory KPIs.
- Conducted SKU rationalization to improve product portfolio management of 1200 SKUs and trim slow moving inventory.

EDUCATION

Dartmouth College | Thayer School of Engineering

Master of Engineering Management – Operations & Supply Chain Management

Hanover, NH

2017

University of Manchester

Manchester, UK